Finding Aid for the Brian Urquhart Collection of Material about Ralph Bunche, ca. 1932-1972
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Suez Canal 2., January-March 1957.; [Box 12, 4 folders]
  - Cables: Burns, Secretary General, Seggen, Cordier, Reddy, Burns-R.J. Bunche Top Secret., March 8, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Top Secret Cable: Burns-Secretary General., March 10, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Memo., May 21, 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cables from UN Emergency Force. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes from Ghana's Independence., March 1957. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Suez Canal 3, Egypt / Israel., March-December 1957.; [Box 13, 6 folders]
  - New York Times index., 1957. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - List Near East meetings w/Secretary General. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche Cabinet II Master List. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Index of A/Documents & Resolutions. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche Notes., March 10-18, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Articles re R.J. Bunche & Gaza. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-King Gordon., March 15, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Burns, Cordier, Reddy, Seggen, Secretary General, Ely, Stavropoulos, some Top Secret, confidential, restricted, some priority UN Emergency Force. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Question of Canadian troops., March 14, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes Gohar; Fawzi. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche Notes., March 19-29, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cables: Secretary General, R.J. Bunche, Burns, Cordier, Reddy, Ely, Professor Bokhari, Khalil, Wheeler, many Top Secret, some priority UN Emergency Force. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., March 30-April 6, 1967. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters: Secretary General-Golda Meir, Fawzi-Secretary General., March 19, 1957 & March 29, 1957 March 1957. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Statement by Secretary General re Middle East., March 22, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Confidential Egypt/Israel background information., March 20, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Statement by Mr. Pearson., March 23, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Burns, Seggen, Secretary General, Cordier, many restricted & top secret, UN Emergency Force. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Keesing's., May 18-25, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Confidential meeting Advisory Committee on UEF., April 15, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Transcript of Secretary General's press conference., April 25, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Statement by Secretary General., April 1, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letters: Golda Meir-Secretary General (); top secret Fawzi-Secretary General. () with declaration on Suez Canal; Secretary General - Ben-Gurion ()., April 1, 1957 & April 9, 1957 April 3, 1957 & April 24, 1957 April 28, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Press release: Secretary General on Wheeler., April 8, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cables: Martola, Burns, Leary, Seggen, Secretary General, Ben-Gurion, R.J. Bunche, Shastri, Cordier, some restricted. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., May 9-11, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Confidential meeting of Secretary General w/Ben-Gurion., May 9, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Shastri, Power, Burns, Cordier, Secretary General, Samper, some top secret. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Memo to D.T. Clements on planning for an Emergency Force., June 17, 1957 & June 26, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Letter: Fawzi-Secretary General., June 18, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., September 14-21, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Aide memoirs., September 5, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cooperation between UN Emergency Force & Israel Authorities. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General., September 19 & September 25, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UNEF Grab Bag., September 24, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes (), Vienna Trip ()., July 8-October 20, 1957 October 13-20, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UN Yearbook The problem of Mt. Scopus., 1957-58. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - UN memos re study of UN Emergency Force & military aspects of UN Emergency Force., December 19, 1957 December 30, 1957. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Confidential meeting Advisory Committee on UN Emergency Force., June 2, 1959. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- UN Emergency Force Photos., 1956.; [Box 14, 1 folder]
  - Original re General Assembly at 562nd & 565th plenary meetings., November 1-February 1956 and November 4-May 1956. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Original U.N.E.F. photos. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - United Nations Under-Secretary Bunche comes to Gaza., 1957. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      "UN 53656 -- Gaza, 11 March 1957 -- U.N. Under-Secretary Ralph Bunche today came to Gaza for a 24-hour visit. He is shown here stepping off his plane, after arriving by air from Abu Suweir, the base camp of the U.N. Emergency Force (UNEF) in Egypt. He was accompanied by Maj. Gen. E.L.M. Burns, Commander of UNEF. Dr. Bunche will visit some of the units in the Gaza area; he will also confer with staff officers of the Force and officials of the U.N. Relief & Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA)."
  - Two pamphlets: Regulations for the U.N.E.F. & Regulations for the U.N.E.F. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Medal., 1956. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Lebanon, Jordan., 1958.; [Box 14, 5 folders]
  - Near East General Documentation., 1958. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet: U.N. Observation Group in Lebanon. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - New York Times index., 1958. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., August 30-September 6, October 11-18, October 25-November 1, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 11 Landing in Lebanon from White House Years. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Secretary General's annual report., June 16, 1958-June 15, 1959. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - UN Yearbook., 1958. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Burns, Stavropoulos, Michaelsen, Sloan, Rosengren, Stedman, Secretary General, Fletcher, Seggen, many top secret. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - UN Emergency Force study group., January 3 & 15, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Assignments on UN Emergency Force Study., February 3, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-T.F. Power (); R.J. Bunche-Burns ()., February 14, 1958 March 14, 1958 & March 24, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Cables: Secretary General, Burns, Seggen, R.J. Bunche, Cordier, Rikhye, many top secret. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters: Burns-Daughton (); R.J. Bunche-Burns ()., April 2, 1958 April 4, 8 & 14, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., May 17-24 and July 19-26, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Hebrew press summary., May 14, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Mount Scopus history. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Secretary General annual report., June 16, 1957-June 15, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., February 15-22, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notes, cables, re R.J. Bunche's Mt. Scopus mission. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-S. Rifa'i. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Report: firing incident May 26 on Mt. Scopus., June 7, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Chronology of Lebanese question in UN., July 25, 1958.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Article: UN Observation Group in Lebanon. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Cables: Burns, Secretary General, Cordier, W.M. Brown some secret. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notes on meeting w/Mr. Lodge., June 17, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-O. Loutfi, Fawzi-Secretary General. Draft: Security Council resolution re Lebanon., June 30, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notes on meeting with C. Malik () & with Dr. Askoul () & R.J. Bunche with Wadsworth ()., July 9, 1958 July 10, 1958 July 17, 1958. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - UNR's Security Council & Middle East., August 1958. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., August 9-23, 1958, October 11-18, 1958, August 30-September 6, 1958, October 25-November 1, 1958, November 15-22, 1958, December 13-20, 1958, February 13-20, 1960. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes on UN Observer Group in Lebanon. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Burns, Rikhye, Secretary General, Cordier. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Meeting re Security Council resolution & UN Observer Group in Lebanon. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes w/Hammarskjold., December 1958. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Bang - Jensen Case., 1958-1959.; [Box 14, 1 folder]
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, B.Goldwater. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Letters: including 1 Typescript (carbon), R.J. Bunche, Goldwater. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Record of hearings of committee on Hungary., December 22, 1959.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Press conference., December 16, 1957, January 21, February 6, 1958, March 3, 1960. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Middle East., 1959-1960.; [Box 15, 3 folders]
  - Near East General Documentation & meetings w/Secretary General., 1959. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - New York Times Index., 1959. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Memo: re Israeli goods., January 7, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Secret notes re Fawzi in Cairo., January 21, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Strictly confidential Secretary General meeting w/Tekoah., February 3, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Message Fawzi-Secretary General., Typescript (carbon) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cable: Copenhagen-U.N., R.J. Bunche Burns, Secretary General, secret. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - UN Yearbook., 1959. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - R.J. Bunche notes re Periclean Club speech., February 13, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Letters: Secretary General-Ben-Gurion, Secretary General-Tekoah. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cables: R.J. Bunche, Rikhye, Burns, Seggen, some top secret. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Memo: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General re Palestine police., March 4, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Message: Secretary General-Fawzi., April 4, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Press conference Secretary General., April 16, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes re UN Emergency Force trip., 1959. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Talks w/Nasser, Fawzi, Golda Meir, Ben-Gurion (at SDE Boker). (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Itineraries re UN Emergency Force trip. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche interviews. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cable: Cordier to R.J. Bunche re birth of his first grandson., April 21, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., September 12-19, 1959, February 13-20, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cables: some top secret re Palestine troops and government (); re raids, firing & air activity ()., May 1959 July 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., August 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Outline of issues for meeting Secretary General w/Tekoah., September 8, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Articles from Minneapolis Sunday Tribune., September 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lists for contents of cables., May-December 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Message Secretary General from Z. Sabry (); Fawzi (); Rocinski ()., December 15, 1959 December 16, 1959 December 21, 1959. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Draft of Black's statement. (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Congo., 1960.; [Boxes 15-16, 5 folders]
  - Pamphlet: UN & Congo: some salient facts., February 1963. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Letter: N. Mason-R.J. Bunche., October 27, 1961. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Press release: R.J. Bunche & Congo., August 30, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - First draft of History of the UN in the Congo June 20-July 14, 1960 by I. Berendsen. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Essay: UN Operation in the Congo. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche Memo notes., April 17-September 13, 1960 and April 26-December 29, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche diary., June/July 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche calendar., July 25-August 30, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General., June 20, 1960.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-Secretary General re rep. in Congo Independence () & confidential (); M. Patrice Lumumba-Secretary General ()., June 20, 1960 June 27, 1960 June 30, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - A. Morrison's article: R.J. Bunche: His toughest assignment. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Secretary General's message re Congo Independence., June 30, 1960. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Confidential letter: Secretary General-R.J. Bunche., April 7, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Letters: H. Samper-R.J. Bunche (); R.J. Bunche-R.J. Bunche Jr., July 7, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Cables: Seggen, R.J. Bunche, R.J. Bunche press conference., December 22, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Document S/4382. A.W. Cordier's Challenge in the Congo. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Meetings in Secretary General's office., July 19-20, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Written correspondence R.J. Bunche-Secretary General. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's Close calls and tight spots. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Letter: confidential Secretary General-R. Rothschild. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Memos: Secretary General-R.J. Bunche & R.J. Bunche-Linner re Rothschild's letter. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Meeting in Secretary General's office., August 6, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Cables & transcripts Secretary General- R.J. Bunche. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - List of contents of cables., August 1960. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Confidential notes re conversation w/Lumumba., August 12, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Record of 901st meeting., September 14, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Document S, 194417/Add.7. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - New Yorker., August 20, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Hammarskjold's Chapter 17 The General Assembly: September-December 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Press conference: R.J. Bunche at UN Headquarters., September 1, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - World News Service., September 2, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Report: alleged assassination plots., November 20, 1975. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - T. Kanza's P. Lumumba. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-C.P. Cabell, R.J. Bunche-A.W. Dulles, R.J. Bunche-R.Kennedy, R. McGill-H.M. Jackson, Secretary General-Aronstein & Botson. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Arrest of Lumumba., December 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Record Appendix., September 20, 1960. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Secretary General-Permanent Mission Belgium. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Congo., 1961.; [Box 16, 4 folders]
  - B.E.U.'s Hammarskjold 1961: The First Months. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Secretary General's annual report., June 16, 1960-June 14, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - UN Yearbook., 1961. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Top Secret Cables: Seggen, Dayal, R.J. Bunche, Abbas, Maceoin, Linner. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Letters: V.M. Stamper-R.J. Bunche, professor Slosser-R.J. Bunche, R.R. Schutz-R.J. Bunche, Secretary General-R.J. Bunche. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Keesing's., June 17-24, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's itinerary., June-December 1961. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Top secret cables: Seggen, Linner, Typescript (carbon) Secretary General, R.J. Bunche, MacEoin. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Hammarskjold's Chapter 21 Vindication & Tragedy & Epilogue. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - H.H.Humphrey's statement re Congo situation., September 21, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cable: Gunnar Jahn from RJG re Secretary General's nomination for Nobel Peace Prize. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - B.E. Urquhart's speech re Dag Hammarskjold., 1973. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Confidential note on meeting of African group., October 19, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche statement re Hammarskjold's Nobel Peace Prize. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - vol.6 U Thant of Secretary General's papers., 1976. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-J.W. Warnock, R.J. Bunche-Urquhart. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Report: Secretary General on Kitona. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Declaration by Mr. Tahombe., December 21, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement re Kitona. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Press conference by R.J. Bunche., December 22, 1961. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Letters to and from R.J. Bunche re U.N.'s role in Katanga. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Congo., 1962.; [Boxes 16-17, 3 folders]
  - Documentation. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - New York Times index., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - United Nations Peacekeeping 1946-1967: Documents and Commentary III Africa by R. Higgins., 1980. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - View from the UN: U Thant., 1978. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Secretary General's annual report., June 16, 1963-June 15, 1964. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Yearbook of UN., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Letters from/to R.J. Bunche. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - R.J. Bunche's diary., March, June-December 1962. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Congressional Record., April 3, 1962-April 24, 1962. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Statements by R.J. Bunche re candidacy for Senate., Typescript (carbon) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Introduction to Secretary General's annual report., June 16, 1962-June 15, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - T.J. Dodd's Congo: The Untold Story. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Various cables re Tshombe., 1962-1963. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Draft memo: R.J. Bunche-Harrison re Air division., October 1962. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - R.J. Bunche's notes re Congo. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Letter: R. Gardiner-Gbenye. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cables: Mathu, Gardiner, R.J. Bunche. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Top secret operation instruction no.1 of., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Letters: R.J. Bunche-Kebbede Guebre, R.J. Bunche-E.A. Gullion, R.J. Bunche-Mrs. E. Edwards, written: R.J. Bunche-Jane & other correspondence from Congo. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Top secret: Operation Tusker., 1962. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Congo., 1963.; [Box 17, 3 folders]
  - Report to Secretary General re UN & O.N.U.C. by R.J. Bunche., Typescript (carbon) (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Letters, R.J. Bunche to: V. Betts, J.M. Wellman, Secretary General. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Interview w/Lieutenant General Prem Chand., August 19, 1982. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Cable: from Bennett. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - UN Yearbook., 1963. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche diary., January/February 1963. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Secret cables: R.J. Bunche, Secretary General, Seggen, Gardiner, B.E. Urquhart re Kamina & Tahombe. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Top secret minutes Katanga area conference., January 6, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Confidential report re Jadotville Operation. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche press conference., January 9, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - A. Stephenson reports., 1963, 1982. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - R.J. Bunche diary., February 1963. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Congo correspondence., 1963. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper articles re Congo. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Comments on 'An Ugly Force in Africa'., February 8, 1963. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - J. Davenport's An Ugly Force in Africa., February 1963. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Force Commander and Senior ONUC Force Officers visit to UN Headquarters., April 1963. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Secretary General's annual report., June 1963-June 1964. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper articles., June 1963. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes on European trip., June-August 1963. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., August-December 1963. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's memoir re European trip., Typescript (carbon) (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - R.J. Bunche's diary., September-December 1963. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Bunche's Speeches Regarding the Congo., [Box 17, 1 folder]
  - D.Hammarskjold's memorial lecture by R.J. Bunche on the topic The UN Operation in the Congo., March 16, 1964. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Draft and final.
- Yemen,; Ralph J. Bunche's Mission Trip., 1963-1964 February 24-March 7, 1963.; [Box 18, 5 folders]
  - Background on UN Yemen Observation Mission/Yemen including list of archive groups. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Excerpt from public papers of Secretary General: The Yemen Question., April & June 1963-1964. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Introduction to Secretary General's 18th annual report., August 20, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Keesing's., March 16-23, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Letters: R.J. Bunche-von Horn. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper articles., February 1963. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - YUN., 1963. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Memos and cables re Yemen-R.J. Bunche trip. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., March 1963. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Confidential special report to Secretary General by R.J. Bunche re visit to Yemen., February 27-March 7, 1963.; Typescript (carbon) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - R.J. Bunche's visit to Aden & talk w/President Nasser., Typescript (carbon) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., March 4-15, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's statement from Cairo., March 6, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - R.J. Bunche's itinerary., March 14-18, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Yemen-R.J. Bunche trip press coverage., March 1963. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Secret: Terms of disengagement accepted by Faysal & Nasser., April 12, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Keesing's., February 8-15, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Confidential UN Observer group for Saudi Arabia-Yemen frontier., April 24, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Secretary General report: re Yemen., April 29, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Letters: E.S. Hope-R.J. Bunche, Secretary General-J.M. Baroody. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Interview with President Abdullah As-Salal by Soviets., April 30, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Record of 1039th meeting., June 11, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Report: Egyptian Air Raids on Saudi Arabia. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Memo: UN Yemen Observation Mission on Royalists. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Cables: Secretary General, Rikhye, R.J. Bunche, Gyani, Nekunam, some top secret. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Memo: R.J. Bunche-A.MacFarquhar re UN Yemen Observation Mission commander. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Letters: personal & confidential to/from R.J. Bunche re Yemen mission. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes: meeting w/M.Fawzi., October 8, 15, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes: meeting w/R.Pharoun & Baroody., October 9 and 21, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Amran convention resolutions. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes: meetings w/Fawzi (), & w/Baroody (), & w/Al-Aini ()., October 25, 1963 October 30 & October 31, 1963 November 1 & November 4, 1963. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - R.J. Bunche's notes., November-December 1963. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Kashmir,; Ralph J. Bunche Trip - UN Missions., 1964-1967 April 7-21, 1964.; [Boxes 18-19, 4 folders]
  - New York Times index., 1964. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - List of confidential papers on Indo-Pakistan conflict., April-August 1971. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Excerpts from a book by S. Bailey: Case 2: Kashmir, 1947-79 & Statement to the Press: New York August 24, 1965. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - UN Yearbook., 1964. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Letters & cables re R.J. Bunche & UN peace missions. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Press release: R.J. Bunche visits UN peace missions., April 7, 1964. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Papers re R.J. Bunche trip to United Nations Military Observer Group in India and Pakistan., May 1962. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Includes secret jeep time travel chart.
  - R.J. Bunche diary., January-April 1964. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - R.J. Bunche's report to Secretary General re United Nations Military Observer Group in India and Pakistan., April 1964. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Excerpts from Secretary General's public papers: situation in Kashmir. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - YUN., 1965. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Keesing's., December 4-November 1965. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Secretary General's report on cease-fire agreement, cease-fire line, & United Nations Military Observer Group in India and Pakistan in Kashmir., September 3, 1965. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Security Council's Resolution 211 at 1242nd meeting () & Secretary General's report () and addendum ()., September 20, 1965 September 21, 1965 September 23-24, October 4, 1965. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Secretary General's report on Security Council's Resolution 210, & Resolution 215., October 1, 1965 November 25, 1965. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Report: The problem of Kashmir. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - R.J. Bunche notes., January 1965. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Letter: R.J. Bunche-R.H. Nimmo., Typescript (carbon) (Box 18, Folder 8)